Guide to the Michael Marrinan papers
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Michael Marrinan papers
circa 2003-2007
SC1265
Marrinan, Michael
2 Linear feet (3 boxes)
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Restricted 75 years from date of creation. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Michael Marrinan has taught at Stanford since 1989, after teaching nine years at Columbia University in New York. HIs principal area of research is the art and culture of France from the 18th to the 20th century. He has written books on the political meaning of history painting (Painting Politics for Louis-Philippe, 1988), and the visual culture of nineteenth-century Paris (Romantic Paris, 2009). He has just completed a book on the French painter Gustave Caillebotte. His secondary interests include how knowledge in general is presented in visual form (The Culture of Diagram, written with John Bender, 2010). In 2007 he co-directed a year-long seminar at Stanford sponsored by the Mellon Foundation called "Visualizing Knowledge: From Alberti's Window to Visual Arrays". He has also co-edited volumes on description in the 18th century (Regimes of Description, 2005) and the digital legacy of Walter Benjamin's Kunstwerk essay (Mapping Benjamin, 2003). He was a Guggenheim Fellow in 1989 and a Senior Fellow at the Getty Research Institute in 2011.
Biographical text from: https://art.stanford.edu/people/michael-marrinan
Scope and Contents
The materials consist primarily of departmental files and personnel files. Also included are lecture preparation files and correspondence.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Art and Art History.; art education
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH.2015-132
  - Daily logs-notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - H.R. stuff (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - VPUE stuff (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Facilities stuff (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty affairs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Faculty meeting notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Department review (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Department chairs information (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clapp fund (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Donor stuff (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Christensen (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Library items (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - VRC stuff (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - VRC curator (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bylaws-voting (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mentoring (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dean stuff (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Provost (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mellon post-docs (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - WIM stuff (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ATS stuff (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Building stuff (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Design TA (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cantor Center stuff (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ARB Facilities (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Summer session (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Department of Art and Art History, FY, 2005/2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Film and Media Studies program-3 year program plan (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Grad Aid, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Grad Aid Survey (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Grad Aid Budget (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Grad students discretionary (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Elis (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Liz Martin (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Junior Faculty stuff (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Branch (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bukatman (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dawson, Bob (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Gough (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pam Lee (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Pam Lee (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Levi stuff (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - MA stuff (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Barbaro, M-R (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Maxmin (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Pentcheva (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Takeuchi (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Turner (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Vinograd (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Gail Wight (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Gail Wight stuff (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Chairs council (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Promotion dummy file (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Film search (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Sculpture search (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous grad students (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Rapp (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Unsolicited personnel file (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Faculty informational packet (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Witman (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Wittman (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Salary stuff (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Adjuncts, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Office reorg. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Facilities, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Chair's fund (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Ops Comm. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Finance-miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Summer-Faculty funds, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Projected budget (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Replacement teaching (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exec. Comm. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Search request (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - EMA/Sudac (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lectures/Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MA Appointment Papers/MA final (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Planning document (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Art building planning (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Commencement (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Am Art stuff (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Burkhardt (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gallery stuff (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Courses (Box 3, Folder 7)